One of the most used implicit intents
in Android is the share intent. It's [LAUGH]
awesome. It's a great way to waste time
for both you and your friends. [SOUND] [LAUGH].
>> Dan!
>> You can leverage your favorite apps to share photos, texts,
videos and general links. And the best part is you don't have
to even know what the user's favorite apps are. Just tell
Android what data you want to share and it shows your users
a list of apps that will share it. Apps that
may not have existed when you app was written. To
make it even easier to share Android 4.0 added the
share action provider and we have it for previous releases of
Android as part of a support library. It operates using
the action send intent. If we use Raytoe's glorious envelope metaphor,
it would be addressed to anyone who could perform action
send. The data descend would be included with it as extras
either as text, or URI to the binary data. And
the MIME type would indicate what the URI points to.
Here's what the share action provider will bring to
our app: the glorious wire frame. There will be
an additional icon in the action bar which will
drop down a menu when clicked to reveal potential
share actions. Another icon will be added to the
right of this one that contains the last application
shared to. Add a ShareActionProvider to the fragment within
DetailActivity. It will share weather in the following format.
Yes, it's just the string we passed into the view plus #SunshineApp.